♪ In the not too
distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
than you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Let's go! ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
♪ Pan left ♪
♪ Gypsy ♪
♪ Hi girl ♪
♪ Tom Servo ♪
♪ What a cool guy ♪
♪ Croooow ♪
♪ He's a wisecracker ♪
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La la la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself ♪
♪ It's just a show I
should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
- [Announcer] 30 seconds
to commercial sign.
- Hey everybody, welcome
to the experiment.
- [Announcer] Commercial
sign in 15 seconds.
- We're playing hide and
seek with the elusive
and inexplicable forces
which control the universe.
- We're still safe because
the cosmic universe
has it's eyes closed,
and it's counting to
6.02x10 to the 23.
- I wanted to play hopscotch
with the impenetrable
mystery of existence.
But he stepped in a wormhole
and had to go in early.
- [Announcer] Commercial sign
in five, four, three, two,
commercial sign now.
- I'll be right back.
(upbeat music)
- [All] 97, 98, 99, 100!
- Ready or not here we exist,
oh look the cosmic universe
isn't even trying to hide.
- Rats.
- Oh and the feckless ubermontzs
are flexing their zykeis again.
Huh?
- Huh?
- The science is
barking down my snorkel.
Oh.
- Oh.
- Okay this is how it goes
down, there's the chorus,
and then you come
in after the bridge.
(speaking foreign language)
Can you dig it?
Okay and then I start swinging
like it ain't nobody's business!
And then that is if
my chops are in shape.
(chuckles)
You know chops?
♪ Da le de le de da da ♪
♪ De le de de ♪
Forget it, Joel,
what can I do for ya?
- What are you talking
about you called us.
- Oh that's right I called
you, I think you're supposed
to do the invention exchange.
- Okay, this is my invention
exchange, it's called
the radio arm saw, and
it's based on the premise
that carpenters for the
longest time would have
apprentices that would
study under them and do
some of the more mundane work.
And now a lot of young
people go right into
the fast food industry, so
none of the carpenters can
afford 'em, except
for maybe Bob Villa.
But what this has is a
circular saw that I bolted onto
a remote control car.
And you can pan it back now
Cambot and we'll show this.
Now what we got here is a board.
I rev up the car,
okay there it's going.
It's kinda loud now so just
try to pay attention anyway.
And it drives right
across like that.
And it saws the
board right in two.
- What's so great about that?
- It's based on the premise
that the further you are
away from the saw, the
better off you're gonna be.
(chuckles)
- Huh?
- Oh come on, shake it
off Joel, you're okay.
It could happen to anybody.
- You okay Joel?
- No, it's all hot and
it hurts and stuff.
- That doesn't look OSHA
inspected or anything.
But anyway right now
Dr. Forester's gonna jam
on our new invention, right sir?
- That's right thank you Frank.
Now earlier today Joel
I removed my own head
and fused it to the bell
of this baritone sax.
When Frank blows into
the mouthpiece I wail.
- That's right I press
the valve down here.
The music goes round and round.
♪ Whoa ♪
And it comes out here.
- Yes I call this little
invention Dr. Sax.
Now I'd like to play for
you some of my favorite
John Coltrane
charts, hit it Frank.
♪ An evil supreme ♪
♪ Well what do ya think ♪
(coughing)
- You may have just
crossed that line.
I've never seen
anything so hideous.
So immoral, so atonal.
- Thank you, oh I've got to
clean out his spit valve.
- Thank you Frank.
Well Joel your movie this week
is preceded by a little piece
of trite that's very
close to my own heart,
called the phantom creeps,
and it stars our old friend
Bela Lugosi as a lovable
but fractured mad scientist.
Bad print, bad
sound, bad for you.
Deal with it joyless pro.
- Oh we got movie time!
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] My goodness it's
creeping, it's really creeping.
- Aw it looks like a
ding dong with legs.
Ford Beebe.
- [Tom] Ford Beebe.
- [Joel] Ford Beebe.
- [Croooow] Ford Beebe.
- [Tom] Sheila MacRae, I'm
coming, goodnight everybody!
- That's how I looked
like before the shave,
now let's meet the cast.
- [Joel] That's my roommate
Steve, he's always on the phone
and always, always
in the bathroom.
- [Tom] Cindy, she's not half
bad if you know what I mean.
Kinda looks like Madonna.
- Then it's Johnny and Ray,
Johnny's the talkative one.
Ray looks like Madonna.
- [Tom] There's Pete and
Repeat always sticking
their patooey's where they
don't belong either end.
Those were just my friends,
let's meet the cast.
- I forget who did what here,
I say shoot the picture.
Let God sort it out.
(chuckles)
- [Joel] The menacing power,
that would be Conn Edison.
I'm guessing.
(dramatic music)
- Maybe I shaved him too
close, the ultimate test
of the Helsinki formula.
(dramatic music)
Hey I just invented
a Post It note.
- [Tom] Isn't he one
of the Smith brothers?
- Yeah either Trade or Mark
I'm not sure which one.
Now to put him in my stock pot.
- [Tom] I knew him Horatio.
- You're not gonna let that
thing out again are ya?
- Certainly, there's
work to be done of it.
- It might get away
like it did last time.
- [Tom] You dare mock me!
- I created it.
- [Joel] I'm the
God, I'm the God!
- I can control it or destroy it
as I can you, you whom I
helped escape from prison.
Quickly.
- [Tom] I'm gonna give
him such a pinch, ooh.
- Boy is he in a bad mood.
- [Tom] What's behind
the panel Johnny?
(soft music)
Oil can, oil.
- Cool.
- I don't see what
good it is, the cops
will never let anything like
that walk down the street.
- [Tom] Shut up he
just plays tapes.
- What will the
police, or anybody do
against an Army like that?
- [Joel] Well they could give
him a plastic hassle man,
that's what.
- [Tom] Hello Ben, I'm
Milton, your brand new son.
- Oh what's the big deal,
it's a big metal Richard Keel?
- [Joel] Gomer Pyle reporting
for duty Sergeant Carter,
shazam!
- [Tom] Now how
much would you pay
for an all purpose
master like this?
Wait, there's more.
- He won't be controlled, he
could crush all opposition
and make me the most
powerful man in the world.
- Hey watch it!
- Hey yeah, nice speech,
but he's trashing the place.
- [Tom] He's programed
to do Noel Abram's job.
Fixes in a jiffy.
(dramatic music)
mm,
mm.
Mm.
- Wait 'til I get him
on the straightaway.
- [Tom] Dominoes.
- There's a car outside.
- That will be my wife,
she wants to take me away.
- She's got an extra job.
- She's afraid of what
I'm doing here, and yet
she knows only a
small part of it.
- [Tom] Aha.
No offense for the doily.
- Talk to him alone Dr. Mallory.
He's been angry with you
ever since you refused
to continue to work with him.
- Thanks for the exposition.
- Because he was
working along lines
contrary of the good of mankind.
- [Joel] Hey who doesn't?
Give him a break.
- I hope I can stop him
before it's too late.
- I hate to have
you face him alone.
- Dressed like that.
- I understand, I think
he really cares for me.
As much as he can
care for anybody.
- Except himself.
- [Joel] Well talk about
vicious backstabbing.
- You're not gonna
tell her about
the new element you
discovered are ya?
- [Tom] You mean upsy daysium?
- I have accomplished what
they told me was impossible.
- [Tom] A funny
Gallagher routine?
- The magnetized discs.
- But if you're determined
to face him alone,
I'll wait in there.
- In the sound proof booth.
- But won't your
wife think that?
- Silence!
- [Tom] She knows
nothing of our love.
(knocking on door)
Enter.
- [Ann] Alex!
- Oh don't do that, you
scared the pants off me.
- [Ann] You're glad to see me?
- [Tom] Sure as long
as your lights are out.
Okay now beat it.
- I've been wanting a
witness to my great triumph.
Yes.
I told Mallory and Gathers
that we are on the way
to induce a state of
suspended animation
that couldn't be torn from
death that I could find.
- [Tom] Play a Kenny G album?
- Dream but a fool,
but now I have it.
And you shall see
and tell them, come.
- You've really gone over
the edge this time Croft.
- [Tom] Ooh I love what
you've done with the place.
Now what goes on in here?
- You see this is disc?
Watch.
- This is disc.
- [Tom] Oh I've seen this one.
- [Joel] Now tree, we've
never met before have we?
Good.
- [Tom] What's he
have, sea monkeys?
Sea monkeys, is that what it is?
(dramatic music)
Oh looks like sea monkeys.
This is an outrage.
Ish!
- It will not come to you.
- [Tom] Even spiders have taste.
- It will go only to that disc,
which I have put
there by the plant.
That disc there is
magnetized by a positive ray
with my new element which
is unknown to science.
And this little spider
carries the negative.
When the two meet.
- Aw can the ballon juice broth
and get on with
the parlor trick.
- [Tom] Do that snappy patter.
Shopper always
leaves you laughing,
ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
I can see the string.
Whoa!
- [Joel] That's my new
opening, what do you think?
- Great, you just
invented stop animation.
- The same circumstances.
It's too bad that Mallory's
not here to see my triumph.
- [Joel] Right behind you.
- [Mallory] I have seen it.
- [Tom] Huh, fazed.
- You, you were spying!
- Call it that if you wish Alex,
but you made no secret of it.
Now my fear is what are
you going to do with it.
- I'll put it in your
shorts you little stinker.
- Not hand it over to the
government as you would have me.
- I still think
that would be best.
It should be under control
for the good of mankind.
You would still receive
credit for it's discovery.
- [Joel] You just won't be
able to do it in any clubs.
- But possibly.
- Never will I let it go!
Already our foul government
has offered me millions.
Perhaps
- [Tom] Thousands!
- I shall sell to them.
- Don't you realize
what a terrific weapon
it will be in the hands
of unscrupulous people?
- I know.
- [Joel] Comedy club owners?
- That is why they shall
pay me dearly for it.
- Alex you must not.
- Then it is my duty to
inform the government at once.
- Ooh what a look I'll give you!
- Alex please!
- [Tom] God Grant me
the serenity to accept
the things I cannot change and.
- Alright, if it is your
duty do so by all means.
But you will find
it a great mistake.
- What do you mean?
(chuckles)
- You shall soon learn.
All of you.
- [Tom] The power
of the dark one.
- I'm sorry but he just
can't help being creepy.
- [Tom] Your
prescription's ready sir.
- Monk, Monk, get
the divisualizer.
Did you print out my
instructions regarding
the work to be done on this?
- Yes sir.
- [Tom] It's an
electronic dance bot.
- Ha I am not afraid.
- [Tom] Haim?
(speaking foreign language)
- They know everything that
I have, but they know nothing
of the divisualizer,
- I think it goes
under the suit.
- it will conceal
me from my enemies.
- I'll stay here tonight,
perhaps I can see him again.
- [Joel] If he'll have
me the big galoot.
- I'll persuade him
from his mad course.
- And I'll get in touch
with the government.
I've already talked
with Captain Lester
at the War Department
about Alex.
- [Tom] And I'll give the names
of my colleagues to
Senator McCarthy.
- No Ann they'll just keep
him and what he has done
under control so that
he can't misuse it
or dispose of it to
a country that would.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Oh oh.
- [Croooow] Uh oh.
- [Tom] I never shoulda filled
up on that four alarm chili.
Ew, excuse me.
(dramatic music)
- Burn the file on the
electric dance belt
and pick up my manhood
it's under the chair.
- You have failed Monk.
- [Tom] Whaddya mean?
I wrote straight no
chaser around midnight.
That's a good thing.
- But I will not fail, I cannot.
- I'll call if I need you.
- And I'll go call Roy Kohn.
- Goodnight.
- [Tom] Fits nice works real,
oh that's no dance belt.
Say that's a pretty
good Patrick Swayze.
- [Alex] It is perfect,
but for a shadow.
- But can you come back?
- [Alex] Surely
I must come back.
- Then I'll go to
Victoria's Secret.
(chuckles)
- [Joel] Think you could
steal me some candy bars
or something some day,
that'd be really cool?
- And now with the
phantom, there is nothing
that I cannot do.
- [Tom] If I had you.
- Just put some lace
on this dance belt.
- [Tom] Now will our mystery
guest sign in please?
- [Joel] Aw he gets
all the neat toys.
- Ah, ah.
Ah, ah.
(dramatic music)
- If you guys don't mind I
got a Michelin Man reading
in an our.
- [Scientist] Nobody can find
our secret workshop without
the iron man helping.
- [Tom] I am Iron Man.
- This'll conceal it
so cleverly, nobody
could ever find it.
- [Joel] Unless they're from
the student loan association.
- I must be entirely
moved by morning.
Pack what we need.
- [Tom] Look at all the
pizzas that guy can hold.
(dramatic music)
I'll just let myself out.
- [Joel] While the cat's
away the mice will play.
- Oh I love what you've
done with the place.
- [Tom] I know I get
compliments always, thank you.
Sorry I didn't have
everything packed,
but sit that down anywhere,
can I get you a beer?
(dramatic music)
- Now turn your head and clank.
- [Joel] Wow this guy
really knows how to
get the most out of what
limited space he's got.
- [Tom] I know he should be in
Better Dungeons and Gardens.
(soft music)
- My private stock,
Glenfittish, 30 years old.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] It's just what
his sinuses needed.
- [Tom] He's just blowing
off a little steam there.
- [Joel] Quick get Vicks
on the phone, I've just
invented the vaporizer.
- The source of all my power.
(upbeat music)
- From what you say Dr.
Zorka has discovered
something very important.
- I'm sure he has,
highly dangerous too.
- [Tom] Seal a Meal?
- Dd7.
- [Tom] Snackmaster?
- Have you made
any search for it?
- No, we thought we'd better
wait until you got here.
- [Tom] Who are you anyway?
- Let's look in his laboratory.
- Aren't you gonna
take that disc?
- I'll get it later I'd hate
to have one of those spiders
find it in my pocket.
(laughter)
- Fools, fools!
Let them search, they
will find nothing!
- [Tom] We'll just
break right in here.
- [Joel] I really like
what they've done in here
with the pastels and
the accoutrements.
(dramatic music)
- A lot of equipment
seems to have been moved.
- You can talk to
Rankin or the spy guide
who'll be with you.
- But.
- Unseen.
- [Tom] Next I'll show you
how to make a bag snagger.
- Your husband smokes
a popular brand.
- [Joel] Columbian.
(laughter)
- He can't stand tobacco.
- How about his assistant?
- He can't stand smoking
his assistant either.
- He's right, you know
Zorka worked alone.
- [Tom] Okay now you be the
chauffer, I'll be the Contessa.
We can play that game.
- We will go.
(chuckles)
(dramatic music)
- We must be more
careful than ever
that no one discovers the
entrance of our secret garage.
- Yeah right, right, right.
- [Tom] Yeah whatever.
- [Joel] Just get in there, get
into this little crawl space
you lard butt, geez.
What a pain, oh brother.
- Well I'll call headquarters
and have his
description broadcast.
He'll be picked up
somewhere, that is if
he still answers
his own description.
- [Tom] I just love
informing on people.
- All clear?
- Yes sir.
- Then we will go to meet
the agent of the spy rings.
- [Tom] A spy ring to what?
- When last seen he
wore striped trousers,
dark hand tie,
and cut away coat.
- [Joel] And a light
blue Warner bra, ooh.
- He it's Gladys Kravitz.
- [Detective] Yes that's right.
Put this on the right away.
- Pick up that man!
- What do you mean,
give him a ride?
- [Tom] No, ask him out,
what do you think I mean?
- He might be useful to me.
- He's just my
type, AB negative.
- [Joel] Hey you guys
going to that Dead concert?
Yeah did you hear Pigpen died?
- Pigpen died?
- [Tom] Pigpen's dead?
(groans)
If Pigpen died I don't
wanna live either.
(tires squealing)
- [Joel] What a long
strange trip it's been.
(dramatic music)
- Hey that's a rental
it's on my card.
- [Tom] I'm dead
now, don't hitchhike,
- The man is dead.
- [Tom] Please.
Don't hitchhike.
- How fortunate, that
simplifies everything.
- [Tom] To you.
- Get Ms. Daisy out of there.
- You will make it seem that
it is the famous Dr. Zorka
that has been killed.
- Ah the old switcheroo.
- [Tom] Good.
- And you will get another
car, go home, and see
what they are doing there.
- [Tom] Then you'll be happy?
I don't think so.
- West speaking.
- [Tom] Just trying to
do what's right, and you?
- Right, I've got it,
we'll fly right down there.
Been a car found wrecked
and burned on Highway 10
50 miles out of here.
- [Tom] On a car phone?
- Ah just the thing
we're looking for.
- [West] The contents
of the pockets
indicate it was Dr. Zorka.
- [Tom] Him I'm speedy
the Alka Seltzer, ha, ha.
- [West] Will you go with us?
- [Tom] It's Cuckoo
the bird girl.
- [Mallory] A sense of shock.
- I'll go, I must know.
- [Tom] If Pigpen's still alive.
- Off the plane.
Whenever you're
ready Mrs. Zorka.
- Put that lampshade on
your head, tie femur bones
around your waist, and dance
naked in the moonlight!
(laughter)
- [Joel] Good one.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] I sure hope
they have those
little salty, sweet
peanuts on this flight.
(dramatic music)
Good thing they still have a
broom closet on this plane.
- They are taking
my wife to identify
the body we left at the car.
She will know it was not mine.
- What the hoot?
- She has one of my discs,
and she does not know it.
I have just time enough to put
that spider into her plane.
- [Tom] Am I wacky or what?
- She will go into
suspended animation
so that she cannot
identify the dead man.
Then I will take her
from them and revive her.
- [Tom] Only to put her
back to sleep again.
- Quick, you have to be there
as soon as the plane arrives.
(dramatic music)
- I like this so much
I bought the company.
- [Man In Black] It
shouldn't take long.
- I'll check the lab equipment
and try to figure out
just what's missing, goodbye.
Goodbye.
- Bye.
Bye.
- So long.
- [Tom] Bye, bye.
So Bill ever flown one
of these shuttles before?
- [Joel] Uh oh raid!
(dramatic music)
- Is there something in
there with that door,
I'm sure I shut it?
- [Pilot] Doesn't look
to me as if you did.
- Wiener.
- [All] Whoa!
- [Ann] This wasn't in my
bag when I left the house.
- [Tom] You know if you bite
one of those it'll spark
in the dark.
- This looks like
- the same kind of piece
that went under the plant.
- [Ann] The one
the spider went to.
- Are you certain it
wasn't in your bag before?
- Positive.
- [Tom] Are you sure
you're not a clepto?
- [Jim] Let me see it,
I haven't seen one
of those things yet.
- Roll over will ya, Jim?
I want to send it back
to the department.
Are you sure you didn't
find it and take it as sort
of a keepsake?
- Why of course I didn't.
- Tell me from where
the car was found,
have you any idea where
Dr. Zorka was going?
- None!
(screaming)
- Well the pilot's bombed.
- The propeller's out of
order we have to bail out.
(snoring)
(engine roaring)
- [All] Whoa!
- What are you doing in here?
Nevermind, get out!
- [Tom] I'm the automatic pilot.
- Huh?
- [All] Oh!
Oh!
- Get into this suit.
- Yes.
- [Joel] Oh, Captain Spalding.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Charlie
Sheen, Navy Seals.
- Nice.
- [Joel] Nice, I think we're
gonna get out of here soon.
- Uh oh.
Hey bumble's bots.
(dramatic music)
(applause)
- Alright, welcome to
Bela's Okay Discoveries.
My name's Joel, a product
that can allow you to make
anything at all explode,
we'll see it on today's show.
Then we'll be showing
you how to make
your neighbor's house
turn into instant rubble.
But that's in the
second segment.
Now I'll introduce my guests,
Tom Servo and Croooow.
(applause)
- [Croooow] Thank you.
- Thank you everybody,
and good day to you Joel.
Now what we have here,
can we pan over here and
get a little look at these?
Down here it's called
The Phantom Creep.
Now it's been in use for
Great Britain for years
but not a lot of
people in the states
know anything about it.
- Looks like kind of a spider.
- Yeah that's right,
now let's take a look
at this shirt here that
we've prepared ahead of time.
It's been smeared
with axle grease,
a little blood, some chocolate,
and a little
polychlorinated biphenyl.
- Oh I know Cambot
and I wouldn't want
that to happen to us.
(applause)
- Okay, so what we want
you to do is attach
one of those little discs there
that you have in your hand.
- This disc, that's it?
I love it!
Okay, how much would you pay?
- We're not there yet.
- Okay, so we attach
the disc to the shirt
and we bring in our
little Phantom Creep.
Now there it goes, can you see?
- Can you see?
There it goes.
- There it goes
right in there and!
(applause)
- I love it.
(chuckles)
- That's amazing isn't it?
- Okay, now quickly
Joel, Joel, Joel,
now grab that
satellite dish there.
Grab the dish, there you
go, you see what he's going?
He's bending over,
he's grabbing the dish.
- This is amazing people,
it's absolutely amazing,
now watch.
- Take the dish, now rub
some black dirt into it.
Just some ordinary black dirt.
- We can take it right off
his shirt there if we want to.
- But this is, I can't this
is my satellite, come on!
- Oh it will be fine,
it's okay I promise.
- But it's right off
the satellite of love.
Okay, alright.
- It's okay.
- Alright come on,
just like that?
- Now everyone knows
the side facing the sun
takes a real beating, I mean
it's 4,000 degrees out there.
The other side,
no sun over there.
What happens when
I stand over here?
- You're out of the sun?
- That's right, it's
ice cold over here.
We take a little disc.
- Take one of those discs.
- We put it right in the center.
And here it comes.
- Watch.
- You'll see.
Ah!
- Isn't that amazing huh?
- That's fantastic,
okay, I love it.
My heart says yes, but
my heart says how much?
- Okay now Joel, if
you were to sneak into
a mad scientist's lair
tried to buy all this,
well it would cost you well
into the millions wouldn't it?
- That's right Servo, right.
The genetic engineering
alone would run
hundreds of thousands of
dollars not to mention
the arachno pyrotechnics.
- Alright, you know
me, I'm a hard sell.
Come on let's make a deal.
Make it better.
- Now I'm glad you asked
us for that, we're gonna
sweeten the deal a
little bit for you here.
Now we're gonna throw
in the napalm spider.
- Uh-huh, uh huh, that's
this right here right?
- That's right.
- Now is that jelly gasoline?
- Oh it's not just
jelly gasoline Joel
but a highly effective
anti-personnel device.
- I see, okay, but
what's the deal?
They're like three spiders.
- Well we've got
the napalm spider,
the defoliant spider, and mint.
- Alright, but can't you make
it just a little bit better?
Come on everybody.
- Come on Joel, Joel,
we're business men.
- Alright, alright I'll tell
you what we're going to do,
since you're a friend
of ours we're going to
throw in or grab that
tray down there will you?
- Get the tray,
- 'Cause my arms are
inoperative, so I can't grab it.
- he's grabbing the
tray, there we go.
- Is this what
we're talking about?
Looks like a really big spider.
- That's the granddaddy of
all explosive spiders Joel.
This one can take out
a whole city block.
Now where's that disk Croooow?
- Well Servo the amazing
thing is I've slipped that
lightweight disc
into Joel's pocket.
(applause)
- And he's right it really
is comfortable, I'll take it!
- I like this Phantom Creep bit.
Reagan's deregulation of
television really pays off.
- If you've got
your charge card out
I'd like to get the
Snackmaster thing.
- Well as you know Joel
the torture never stops
around here that's what
you get from hanging out
with guys like us.
One more bad film.
No, no, no, no, no,
don't pass out on me now.
Go ahead put in the tape Frank.
Taste my steel pasty
boy, after this.
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Robert L. Lippert.
- [Joel] Armida is that Spanish?
- [Tom] A Spanish Armida.
Oh Smoki Whitefish,
sounds delicious.
- [Joel] Hmm Fred Coby
the cheese magnet.
Rowdy Rubles.
- Zack Williams is
Semiaand Chief Zabu.
- [Tom] Norman Cerf the best
editor to come out of the
agrarian feudal
collective system.
(dramatic music)
- I'll have a Carl Berger.
- [Joel] Original song There's
No One In My Heart But Me.
- By Dr. Christian Barnard.
- [Joel] Hmm Jo Pago
based on a pasta dish.
- [Tom] Joe Pagano
was based on and idea
by William Stephens?
(dramatic music)
That's wrong Collins,
smarter brother.
- Mar's extending us a welcome.
- [Tom] Hey look a Shriner.
I don't remember the name
but the fez is familiar.
- [Joel] So anyway I'm
flying one of those
new flying carpets they
got and it's great.
- Enjoy the only exterior shot.
- [Tom] Portugee
Joe's, they've got
the wet grass skirt night.
Enjoy the fenduzler
and keep the cup.
- Donner party of three please.
♪ That summer night I
tried to pass you by ♪
♪ I smiled at you ♪
♪ You smiled at me ♪
♪ We all smiled at each other ♪
♪ We smile ba bum ♪
- [Joel] You know that piano
player's not bad, and the girl,
I'll probably date
her, you know?
Dig it.
♪ You left me so completely ♪
- Excuse me, are
you our waitress.
I'd like to order whatever's
on the wall over there.
♪ There's no one in my heart ♪
- [Joel] Sultry.
- [Tom] Table dance,
hey table dance!
- Whoa, whoa!
♪ In your ♪
- [Joel] She must be enforcing
the two drink minimum.
I'd guess.
- We'd like our check.
♪ Don't want to but I do ♪
- [Tom] We gotta stop bringing
our business lunches here.
- Let me put my eye in, what?
What is that you say?
What?
I can't hear you, hmm?
- [Joel] Do you think
I can get a table
in the no singing section?
Is that possible?
♪ Or a million years ♪
- So I was seeing the
brudisks the other day.
♪ Sharing so patiently ♪
(coughing)
♪ And when you ♪
- [Tom] Joel which
Navy is he in?
- [Joel] I think
he's a cab driver.
♪ I'll burn your
lips with kisses ♪
- [Tom] Burn your lips?
- [Joel] Saigon!
I'm still in Saigon.
♪ There's no one in
my heart but you ♪
♪ And heartburn ♪
(applause)
- [Joel] Freebird!
Freebird!
- Whoo, Freebird!
Whipping post!
- Whipping post!
(cheers)
- Three hours last night.
- I did not tell you
I would be there.
- [Tom] It's a really long song.
- Your said you would.
- Oh but my lips did not.
- [Tom] My dress said
maybe but my patella
gave a resounding yes.
- You're sweet but
dangerous Mr. Simpson.
- Good, then I'm
making progress.
And incidentally Yvonne,
let's stop being so formal.
The name is Bob.
- When I stop being formal,
then it will be
dangerous for you.
- [Tom] Check please!
- I'll give you five minutes.
- For what?
- To start running.
(chuckles)
- Have another drink.
- Oh our boyfriend's here.
- I think you have company.
- [Joel] And his hat
is more authentic.
- [Tom] Say did you
take my red underwear
with the big S on 'em?
- I thought I'd find you
in here, do you realize
we're supposed to take
off in 20 minutes?
- Easy son, easy, have a drink.
- We haven't got time.
- We don't fly for Northwest.
- What do you mean
we haven't got time?
We've got all the
time in the world.
- [Joel] Oh I hate
when he says that.
- Take a look at that.
- [Tom] Hmm what here?
Two more pilots arrested.
- Hmm famous tennis
star becomes woman.
Hmm neat.
- [Tom] Becomes legally
ordained minister.
- The will of Peter Vanderhorn
the multi millionaire diamond
tycoon was probated yesterday.
- [Joel] Hmm sounds painful.
- The rightful reward
of 5,000 pounds sterling
for the discovery of his
daughter Greta dead or alive.
She was returning
home by plane from
an American finishing school
the first day of World War II.
- No, no when you read
it do all the voices.
- The last communication from
the navigator placed the plane
somewhere over the
Zambezi territory.
No word of the plane or
any of the passengers
has ever been received.
- [Tom] Read me my horoscope.
- But so what?
Our business is flying
private passengers.
And I don't want to remind
you son but two of them
are waiting for us right now.
- So what?
Right now we're out of business.
- [Joel] Ow!
- [Tom] Oh oh!
- Ow!
- Look Mike sit down.
- [Joel] I am sitting.
- There's 5,000 pounds reward
there, which is about $20,000
for anyone who finds
Greta Vanderhorn.
And she doesn't
have to be alive.
- You are wacky, that plane
was lost six years ago.
- [Tom] I'm nutty,
I'm J.C. Fickelhoffer.
- What's been lost can be found.
- If that were so the plane
would've been found
a long time ago.
- But they weren't able
to send out search planes
while the war was on.
Now the restrictions
have been lifted
every broken down flyer
on the African coast
will be taking off to look for
the wreckage of that plane.
And we're gonna get there first.
- Who said anything about
getting there at all?
- I did.
He did.
- Yeah he did.
Yep, heard him.
- Right here.
- Totally did.
- I hate to remind you son,
but you're only the junior
partner in this concern.
- [Joel] I know dad.
- I happen to own 3/4
of that crate remember?
- As if you'd ever
let me forget it.
- Then come on Mike,
time is of the essence.
- Yeah, yeah, I know, just
like your old ballet teacher
used to tell you.
- Oh I deserve that good one.
- Some extra tanks of
gas, I think a little trip
in the jungle will do you good.
- [Tom] Oh I went
before we got here.
- [Joel] He's with
me, excuse us.
- There's a man on
the wing of the plane!
- [Tom] What's a five letter
word for rum and Diet Pepsi?
- We should hit Zambezi
territory by morning.
- [Tom] Says you.
- Is that your hand? Hmm.
- [Joel] I think we just
flew through a dissolve.
- [Tom] That's our plane.
♪ Do do do do do ♪
Wow say, these Viewmasters
really bring nature to life.
Look at that.
That's irrelephant.
- [Joel] Hey I see us up there.
- Okay Boy Scout, how
much longer do you intend
to spend on your good deed?
- [Tom] I was in
the ballet division.
- If we collect the reward.
- If we collect it.
- You mean those cookies?
- Like looking for a needle in
a haystack, to coin a phrase.
- [Joel] Is that yours?
- You go on and coin on if it
will make you feel any better.
- Nothing's gonna make
me feel any better
until we're out of this.
Come on bob.
- [Tom] Oh come clean with
me Frank, tell me you haven't
had the urge to ram this
baby into the ground.
- Hey a petting zoo.
Now we're at the Dells.
(upbeat music)
- Mike!
Mike I think I see something.
Here take a look!
- [Tom] Oh yeah that's neat,
hey pop in another slide
for me will ya?
- Could be.
- Well let's go down and see.
- Hey turn back
we're over Nebraska!
- [Tom] Did ancient
astronauts land here
millions of years ago?
- [Joel] Bill not
a crash landing.
- [Tom] No!
- [All] Whoa!
- [Joel] We're pushing zebra.
- [Tom] Oh they had to land,
the rubber bands unwound.
(chuckling)
- You go ahead Bob,
you're the Boy Scout,
ballet division.
- [Tom] Look a tiger.
- What, in Africa?
- [Joel] Shh, hey don't
step in the macoomba.
- [Tom] Ugh.
Nice ensembles for
a couple of guys
who can't remember to gas up.
- Now how do you run this?
- How far away did you
say the wreckage is?
That's kinda personal.
- About a mile.
- North by north east right?
- [Tom] That was a good movie.
(plane crashing and
shooting bullets)
- You keep your eyes peeled
Bob remember we're not in the.
- [Joel] I'll go one better,
I'll take him clean out
of my sockets if you like.
(laughing)
(growling)
- Hello kitty cat.
- [Tom] Breath mint?
(dramatic music)
Spring time and a
young man's fancy
slightly turn to
thoughts of elephants.
- [Joel] Hi I'm
Satan, enjoy the film.
- You're wondering how we can
dominate this aren't you Mike?
- [Tom] Pretty nosy kitty cat.
It looks like they all
just got out of the shower.
- [Joel] Yeah and
they're on a snipe hunt.
- [Tom] Who's got the bag?
We're on the same set at least.
They're all spring
time fresh though.
They're on a collision course
with a whole lot of trouble.
(dramatic music)
- Now I can't fall your ball
anywhere what are you playing,
a Schlesinger five?
I think this hall
breaks to the left.
- Wait a minute Bob!
- I hope that's an
acceptable greeting.
- [Tom] Oops.
Oh sorry, sorry everyone,
now please let's not bicker
over who shot who.
The important this is that
we realize we made a mistake.
Good rifling.
- Feels good in hand.
- [Joel] This will be
good killing stick.
- [Tom] Bobby my satch.
- You can't make me,
you can't make me.
♪ Da da da da da da do ♪
- [Joel] Hey it's
Ginger and Maryann.
- Beautiful.
Greta hair very beautiful.
- [Tom] That's nice, hey look,
stop kissing up to me okay?
- Did you study your
spelling last night?
- The dog ate it.
- Good, then let me hear
you spell beautiful.
- Beautiful?
- [Tom] Let me hear
you spell patronize.
- Beautiful.
- Will this be on the final?
- Ah, yes, beautiful.
- [Tom] S-L.
- B-e
- [Tom] A-V
- a
- [Tom] E
- u
- [Tom] R-Y.
- No?
- T-i-f-u-l.
(chuckling)
- That's wonderful.
- Okay now spell anti
disestablishment Aryanism.
- I think.
- Think.
- [Tom] Stink?
- [Tom] Stink, pink?
- Think.
- [Joel] What is this
a Dr. Seuss book?
Think!
- [Tom] I want out of here.
- More beautiful world of all.
(laughing)
- [Joel] You're like
my best friend of all.
- Thanks for playing.
Sam, where's Quincy?
(speaking foreign language)
- [Tom] Could you
spell that please?
(speaking foreign language)
Second word,
- [Joel] Is it a film?
- [Tom] Sounds like.
- It's a play.
- How do ya like that?
- [Joel] I don't.
(speaking foreign language)
- Look, don't tell
'em that we're white.
- [Tom] I didn't say Simon says.
Okay Simon says.
- Mr. Vanderhorn I presume.
- [Tom] Oh funny.
- You'll not speak until
you've been spoken to.
- Hey what is this,
we know who you are?
You may have these
native buffaloed but.
- Silence!
- [Tom] Ooh, snap.
- Or perhaps you wish me to
turn you over to my subjects.
- [Tom] What spelling?
- French?
- [Tom] Trig, Social Studies?
- Did you hear that Mike?
Her subjects.
- Shut up Bob, you've got us
in enough of a jam as it is.
- Ugara.
- What'd you call me?
I'm first native.
- What happened Ugara?
- White devil kill Zullo,
Fracture speech,
- make fire from long stick.
Lose articles.
- Make noise.
- Zillo dead.
(speaking foreign language)
- [Tom] Sorry wrong scene,
excuse me, pardon me,
I'll just step back.
- You shot Zullo.
- Well we didn't
actually get his name.
- How was I to know?
He came bouncing out of
the jungle with that spear.
But I don't get this, we
came here to find you.
Maybe we made a mistake.
- [Greta] Maybe you did.
- [Tom] A big one.
- Certainly it was a mistake
when you killed Zullo
without justification.
Neither he nor any of the
others would've harmed you.
They would've treated
you like gods,
which they thought you were.
- [Mike] But I still don't
get it, what do you care
about what happened
to that native?
(groaning)
- I would suggest
that you be silent.
The penalty for murder is the
same here as anywhere else.
- [Tom] A plea bargain
to a suspended sentence.
(speaking foreign language)
- [Joel] Not yet, two more
pages, yeah, just step back.
(speaking foreign language)
(speaking made up
foreign language)
- Maybe you wouldn't
mind telling me
exactly what goes
on around here.
- Well we have
activities, craft making.
We make wallets,
Tuesday's the fish fry.
- Innocence or guilt
of you and your friend.
- [Tom] Now, now.
- [Joel] Yeah now
it's your turn.
- Okay let it out
man, yep sing baby.
- Morti Gante
appearing this week.
(drum beat)
- [Joel] And now ladies
and gentlemen the Tropicana
extends a warm Las Vegas
welcome to Mr. Gene Cruppa.
- [Tom] Go Gene go.
Go Gene go, go Gene go.
- Go Gene go, go Gene go, go.
(speaking foreign language)
- [Tom] I now pronounce
you man and man.
- Huh?
- My people have
reached a verdict.
- [Joel] You're
to be extradited.
- Since you had no part
in the murder of Zullo
and in fact tried to
prevent further violence,
- You'll be deep fried.
- you'll be permitted to
return to your plane safely.
- That's nice, when?
- As soon as your friend's
sentence has been carried out.
- What do you mean my sentence?
- It is the will of my
people that you be executed
on the first full moon
which will be eight
nights from tonight.
- [Tom] Oh that
sounds fair, but huh?
- But you can't!
- Easy Bob.
- Look Bob, we'll appeal.
- Just to be sure that you
will not attempt to escape
you will both remain
guarded until the execution.
- [Tom] We're already
pretty guarded.
(speaking foreign language)
Yeah, yeah (speaking foreign
language) okay, get on with it.
- Sheesh.
Boy she really put the
boot to you back there Bob.
- [Tom] I suppose we gotta tip.
I hate cops.
- Had to get the hanging judge.
- Well I've been in
better jails in my life.
- [Joel] That's nothing
to brag about Bob.
- First time I was ever in.
And from the looks of things
it's liable to be the last.
What are you worried about,?
They're not gonna execute you!
I'm the one that got
the death sentence.
How do ya like that Greta
giving us the business?
- [Tom] You're
right, I feel great.
- That dame's gone native.
- Don't squawk to me Bob.
- [All] Squawk,
squawk, squawk, squawk!
- It was your own idea remember,
coming out here to look for her?
We were doing alright
ferrying private passengers
until you decided
that there were
easier ways to make a living.
Boy do I wish I was in
Portugee Joe's bar right now.
- [Joel] Maybe they got
a microbrewery around.
- Long, tall cold ones.
- Yeah well maybe we will yet.
- Put that away!
- Alright, alright, I'm not
gonna use it unless I have to.
- It's a lighter.
- I also managed to hang
onto our hand compass.
- [Mike] Oh good.
- [Joel] Good.
- You're not gonna let
me down are you Mike?
- Don't worry,
we've got eight days
to figure a way out of this.
We're in this together and
we'll get out of it together.
- But I'm the one that shot
that native, and I'm the one
they're gonna execute.
- Relax will you?
Like I said we're
in this together.
- Just kidding.
- [Joel] Uh Quincy,
what do, uh, nevermind.
- You come
(speaking foreign language)
Greta wants talk with you.
No you.
- [Tom] Here have this I gotta
go with Henry Silver here.
- [Bob] Give my love
to (speaking foreign
language) Greta.
- Hey you got a smart mouth.
- [Tom] We gotta split.
(speaking foreign language)
- Means white goddess.
- White goddess.
(upbeat music)
- Hey Joel, so what's the deal
with those magic binocular
things we've been seeing?
- Oh that's an old cinematic
device that filmmakers
of old used to use to
kind of teach the viewer
that they were looking
through binoculars.
Even though if you really
look at your binoculars
it looks just like
a movie screen.
- And so then they just
run totally unrelated
stock footage of animals right?
And not even at
the same altitude.
- Or creatures not even
indigenous to the area?
- Yeah right, in
fact Cambot came
all set up with such things.
They're called gobos
if you want to see 'em.
Gobos are matte box
effects for film.
Okay, you want to try it?
- [Tom] Oh so we'll
just sit here and act
as the brunt of your
little visual joke?
- Yeah that's right,
something like that.
Okay this one is called
the binocular kinda scope.
- Hey get us we're a
piece of stock footage.
(laughing)
- And this one is
the keyhole scope.
- You know you're the
only man for me Servo.
- [Tom] Oh Croooow.
- This is the
high-powered scope scope.
- [Tom] And so the
French Prime Minister
shall receive the quadrant,
look out, look out!
- Okay, this is the
periscope scope.
- I don't care how you do it,
you must sink the Bismarck.
- [Joel] And also the
Driving Miss Daisy scope.
- [Tom] You might
as well be walking
driving this slow Miss Daisy.
- Just watch where you're going.
- Okay, this here
is the microscope.
- [Tom] Go ahead
Croooow you can imitate
a one-celled animal
better than I can.
- I am an amoebae.
- [Joel] Starting to
look a bit more like
the Sammy Davis Jr. scope.
This is the Lucy scope.
- Ah Ricky, turns out
I was never funny.
- Okay, the small
intestine scope.
- [Tom] Ooh I feel so funky,
I need soothing and coating.
- That's what we feel like.
- This is the Jose
Feliciano scope there.
- [Tom] Chico, don't
get discouraged.
- This is the
family circus scope.
- [Tom] Okay, who broke my vase?
- Not me.
- Okay, followed by the
Jack O'Lantern scope.
- Huh? Tricky.
- The glaucoma scope.
What?
- What?
- And if you wanna get
really fancy you add the
family circus scope
with the glaucoma scope
and get the Hubble scope okay?
There's that.
Followed by the Pope scope.
The scope's Monkey Trial scope,
otherwise known as
inherit the windowrama.
The ever popular nope scope.
- [Tom] Oh brother.
- [Croooow] Come on.
- And finally
movie sign-o-scope.
- Oh movie sign!
(yelling)
Ow, ow!
[Greta] Leave us alone.
- [Joel] Oh that binocular
seems pretty good.
- [Tom] That's really cool.
- Yeah.
- [Tom] Cambot had
something like that.
- [Greta] Come here.
- Spread out Sabu
three's a crowd.
- [Greta] Sit down.
- [Tom] Can I order right
away I'm really famished?
- [Joel] Coast is clear.
- Did my father
send you to find me?
- Well not exactly
Miss Vanderhorn.
- What do you mean not exactly?
- Your father's dead.
- [Joel] And my mom?
- Whoops.
(soft music)
- When did he die?
- Not quite a month ago.
- [Tom] My partner shot him too.
(soft music)
- Well I guess you
can throw that away.
- [Joel] Oh it just
came with the frame,
queer looking old duff.
- Never lived to find
out what happened to me.
- Exactly what did happen?
- [Tom] Okay, here it goes, I
was paging through the dailies
and I seen an opening
for a jungle goddess.
- At Hastings on the Hudson.
- [Tom] Meanwhile at
Stately Way Manor.
Miss Harcourt's
School for Girls,
chicks on beds.
- [Greta] It was Sunday
morning September the 1, 1939.
I was listening to the
radio with my roommate,
Helen Phillips.
- [Announcer] In general the
world picture remains the same.
Although the threat of war is.
- She had a really deep voice.
- [Announcer] One moment
please ladies and gentlemen,
I've just been
handed the teletype.
Prime Minister Nevil Chamberlain
has just addressed Parliament
and I quote his exact words.
- [All] Help!
- [Announcer] "I just wanted
to inform you that unless"
"the German government suspends
all aggressive actions"
"against Poland, not later than"
"11:00 a.m. British
Summit time September 3,"
"his Majesty's government
will without hesitation"
"fulfill it's
obligations to Poland."
- [Tom] Well that's good Helen,
now try opening with a joke.
- What are you doing
that for Greta?
- I don't wanna hear anymore.
- [Tom] Those morning
look just great on me.
- So what this is the
United States remember?
Who cares what's
going on in Europe?
- [Tom] I'm rich with
no political standing.
- Oh I'm sorry Greta
I forgot you're dutch.
- Oh that's alright, I'll
have to see Miss Harcourt.
- [Roommate] What
are you gonna do?
- I'm going to take
the first plane home
if I can make reservations.
- But why you're safe here?
- That's beside the point, I
don't want to be stuck here
for the duration, and
if the war breaks.
Well maybe I'll be a
nurse, my first aid course
might come in handy.
- Oh it sounds like a lot of
cooky fun, we'll put on a show.
And once the B2 turns into
guava jelly I'll still be alive.
- Johannesburg is in
a British dominion.
And if war breaks well I, I
want to be with my father.
- [Tom] Avril Herrimen?
- It's Adolph Majou.
- [Joel] Yeah I think so.
- [Greta] After considerable
red tape, I was able to.
- [Tom] I went on some bombing
raids over central Europe.
- [Greta] Which was the most
direct route to South Africa.
It was not easy to
make arrangements to
continue my journey.
- [Tom] It's a mobile home.
- [Greta] A great
deal of confusion.
- [Tom] Filled with Lazy Boys.
- [Greta] Plane
reservations were scarce.
However, I was finally
successful and was able to board
another plane for Johannesburg.
At last I was on my
way to join my father.
- [Tom] We're on our way.
- [Greta] It's
necessary to fly over
the dense African jungle.
- [Tom] And do a lot
of voiceover work.
- [Greta] I engaged
in a conversation
with a very lovely woman.
- [Tom] That I didn't like.
- Of course they will be calling
up John and Herbert both.
Seems so strange, their father
was killed in the last war.
- [Joel] That's great.
- [Tom] Yeah that's
great, now put
a sock in it will ya granny?
- When you've lived as
long as I have child
you'll find it
never pays to worry.
I used to worry terribly
about everything.
Little things and big things.
- [Joel] Orange things
and paisley things.
- What on earth's
the matter with you?
We all be dead soon enough.
- [Tom] Yeah sure, hey my
skull's starting to hurt,
could you clam up?
- Hey what is this the
airplane of Dr. Calligeri?
- [Joel] Bizarre.
Captain and I are out of drinks.
- Ladies and gentlemen we
have just received word
over the wireless that
His Majesty's government
has declared war on Germany.
- So it's happy
hour until we land.
(cheers)
- Every attempt to reach
Johannesburg as per schedule.
- [Tom] That oughta hold 'em.
- Well it's come.
- May the Lord have
mercy on us all.
- [Tom] Well I think
he does accept for you.
- [Joel] Stop her
she's got a gun!
She's got a gun!
- Look out!
- I think you'll
all want to join me.
♪ It's a dance of death, death ♪
♪ It's a dance of death ♪
(soft music)
- [Tom] God save the Queen.
- I figured I was seeing Betty
and the kids for Christmas.
- What about your wife?
- Wonder how long
it will be now?
At least I can send him
a picture of his dad
in a RAF uniform.
- [Tom] Instead of
that darn dress.
Meanwhile on yet another plane.
Uh oh, when you stopped
for fuel did you?
Huh?
- [Joel] We're in trouble,
how's the model doing?
- [Tom] Not too good.
- When you were in flight school
did they teach
you how to scream?
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] So you wanna
tell 'em or should I?
(dramatic music)
Uh oh.
- She's dropping
fast, I better go warn
the passengers to fasten
their safety belts.
- [Joel] Yeah like
that's gonna help.
- [Tom] Airport 42.
- Steve, nevermind, I got
it, kinda my fault, sorry.
Sorry.
- [Tom] Big drag.
- [Greta] By some miracle
I was the only survivor.
- [Tom] By some
plot contrivance.
- [Greta] When I came
to it was morning.
I didn't know where I was, or
how I was going to get help.
- Thanks to my Halston
I still looked fabulous.
- [Greta] Started wandering
through the jungle
to try and get back
to civilization.
- [Joel] I find that
travel really broadens you.
(dramatic music)
- I met neat people like
Roddy McDowell, and you know,
it's really true what they say.
- [Tom] Ooh, that monkey
gave me such a chill.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Well you know what
I think this forest needs
is a woman's touch.
(soft music)
- There I was surrounded
by salad fixings for miles,
and no orange
vinaigrette in sight.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Hey toots, it's me
Satan, catch ya later, ya know?
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Suddenly there
I was, in front of
a rear projection screen,
you know how I hate those.
(growling)
- Kitty.
- [Tom] I screamed and that
seemed to help our relationship.
- [Joel] Oh darn, oh what
a bad time to break a heel.
Oh, oh, daddy.
(dramatic music)
- Then I came upon a
sanitation landfill,
I knew civilization
must be near.
(dramatic music)
- [Greta] It wasn't long that
I started into the jungle
that I was confronted
by a group of natives.
I was really frightened then.
- [Joel] You can't tell
from this shot, but I was.
- [Greta] When suddenly
they started to kneel
in an attitude of worship.
I didn't know why but I felt
safer, so mustering my courage.
- [Tom] I began kicking
them repeatedly.
- Take me to your village.
Huh?
- Huh?
- [Tom] What the? You get that?
- Take me to your village.
- She thinks we speak english.
- [Tom] Yeah sister,
don't give me any crap.
- You
- [Tom] Me.
- Take me.
- [Tom] Take you.
- To your village.
- [Tom] Oh you want us to
take you to our village.
- House, house.
(speaking foreign language)
- [Tom] I'm perplexed by
charmed by this plucky stranger.
- We eat tonight.
- [Tom] Oopsie daisy.
(speaking gibberish)
What's going on,
somebody drop a contact?
Here let me help you.
(speaking foreign language)
You caught us at a bad
time, all of our suits
are out at the cleaners and it
gets kinda randy around here
when all of the women
are away, you understand.
(speaking foreign language)
- Well here's the first
problem, she's covered with fur,
give me a razor.
- [Greta] She was a very
sick girl, and only then
did I realize that they
wanted me to help her.
- [Tom] I'm stared of
her, that seemed to help.
Does this story have a point?
- When Wanama recovered
the natives were sure
that I was a goddess,
when Chief Umbanga died
Ulanga the witch
doctor tried to poison
the natives against me,
but he wasn't successful.
- Well do they still believe
that you're a goddess?
- That's another flashback.
- I was deceiving them
Ulanga the witch doctor
would make short work of me.
- Aha, I'm beginning
to get all this now.
But why did you have
Bob sentenced to death?
- You don't think I
intended to carry that
sentence out do you?
- [Joel] We did.
- [Tom] I was counting on it.
- I was stalling for time.
- Smart girl.
- [Tom] You little minx.
- [Greta] I had to do it, if
the natives thought otherwise
we'd all be dead.
- Well that gives us just
seven days to get out of here.
- Your plane is it alright?
- [Tom] Oh it's terrific.
- [Mike] Now it's
in a little clearing
about a mile from where
your plane crashed.
- Must be the accident zone.
- Trust me, obey my
every command, no matter
how strange it might seem.
- [Joel] Oh wow.
- Tell your friend
to do the same thing.
I'll find a way for the
three of us to escape.
Though I'm not sure
your friend deserves it.
I don't like him.
- Bob's alright, a little
trigger happy perhaps,
but he's alright.
- I don't like him.
- [Joel] Oh Bob's alright,
a little trigger happy.
(drum beat music)
- What is that?
- Must be the late show.
(drum beat music)
(chanting)
- Would it be crass for me to
say the native's are restless?
- The dance of death.
- Oh we'll that's cute.
- Ulanga's working the
natives up into a frenzy.
- What's the snake for?
- Nastassja Kinski.
- Ulanga's pet executioner.
- Why mean he?
- It's a very tortuous death,
the poison works very
slowly and horribly.
- [Joel] Kinda sounds like
the plot of this movie.
(laughter)
(humming)
- [Tom] Tommy Tune,
and Nurse Cunningham.
(humming)
- I think you better go now.
We don't want to
arouse any suspicion.
- Speak for yourself.
- I'll see you again
tomorrow, there's so much
I want to talk to you about.
Everything that's happened
in this last six years.
- It must've taken a
great deal of courage
to stick this out for six years.
Goodnight white goddess.
- Goodnight, and don't worry.
Nagara.
- [Tom] Is the
courtesy van ready?
- Nagara, take this
man back, but remember
no harm must come
to either of them.
We must fulfill the law.
- Yes (speaking foreign
language) Greta.
- [Tom] Kill him, kill him.
- I can't believe he
went for it, chump.
- [Joel] Now Calgon,
take me away!
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] They say it's never
a rock video until
they burn something.
(singing)
Catchy tune isn't it?
- That snake probably had it.
- What's going on out there?
- Seems like the witch
doctor's having a little party.
- [Tom] Am I invited?
- What kind of party?
- The dance of death.
- Tell them to turn the
bass down, I can't sleep.
- [Tom] That was incredible,
now was I dreaming
or was there a dance of
death going on last night?
- My eyes better.
- Sure must like something.
- What do you mean
by that crack?
- How do I know that
the two of you aren't
cooking up something together?
- [Tom] Oh you
know I can't cook.
- Meaning what?
- Meaning this 5,000
pounds reward for little
(speaking foreign
language) Greta,
if you two get out of here
alone you won't have to
split the reward with me.
- Hey good idea.
- I oughta crush your skull.
- [Tom] Ah it's been crushed.
- I'm sorry Mike, I'm sorry,
but this place is giving
me the heebie jeebies.
- [Tom] Oh and I
thought they sprayed.
- Yeah, yeah I guess
I know how you feel.
But like I said, we'll
get out of this together.
- Oh good my clams casino,
charge it to the room.
- You come eat with her now.
- Oh thank you.
- [Joel] Alright.
- Well that's my date,
I'll see you later.
- [Tom] So long sucker.
- This for you.
- [Joel] How about
you and I cooking up
something ourselves
good looking?
- Hey there's an
Inuit pole out here.
- [Joel] Different
strokes you know?
- Hello.
- [All] Hello.
- Tell me where are all
your subjects headed for?
- They're going out
after wild antelope.
They leave early so that
they can be back before dark.
They don't like the
jungle at night.
- But I do.
- Won't you sit down?
- Well thank you white goddess.
- [Tom] Thank you white racist.
- It's been a long time
since anyone called me Greta.
- Alright Greta.
- [Tom] Hey,
buttermilk biscuits.
- Well how does it look?
- Oh, well tell me
what it is first.
- Oh, it isn't what
you might think.
I assure you that the natives
here are not cannibals.
- [Tom] The Scottish
call it haggis.
- That's a relief, did
you cook it yourself?
- Goddess' don't cook,
what I wouldn't give
for a hamburger and some
nice french fried potatoes.
- That's right you went to
school in the states didn't you?
- You're an American aren't you?
- I'm from Colorado, and
speaking of hamburgers
I could go for one myself,
you see I haven't been
home in three years.
Greta do you mind if we
start right in, I'm so hungry
I could eat a horse.
- Hey you're in luck.
- Huh?
- Don't worry, here
they call it zebra,
it's not only edible
but quite delicious.
- Alright if you say so.
- [Tom] Hmm, dark
and white meat.
- It's very tasty.
- Oh white devil on fire.
- Oh wait, wait, wait, wait.
- No, white devil
just having a Kent.
- [Tom] You're not from
around here are you?
- You speak pretty good english.
- Oh sure (speaking
foreign language) Greta
teach me everything.
- Sure you got money G.I. Joe?
- Me very smart.
- Did (speaking
foreign language) Greta
tell you that too?
- Oh sure.
She no tell me what smart mean.
- [Joel] Means your stacked.
- You tell Wanama.
- Well it means sort of like.
- Oh it's just
different that's all.
- Dumb.
- Dumb,
very beautiful, dumb.
- Thought you'd like
it, now get out of here.
- You eat now.
- [Joel] You're still here?
- Why everybody say
you white devil?
- [Tom] 'Cause I kill
indiscriminately.
- You're very, very nice.
- [Joel] Get me,
sentenced to death
and I'm still making time,
yeah I'm pretty cool.
♪ Don't nobody move ♪
- It's hard to believe that
the war lasted so long.
- If it hadn't been
for the atomic bomb.
Tell me Greta didn't you
ever try to get out of here?
- I used to dream
my way out Mike.
- [Tom] Only take
the magic trolley
and click my heels together.
- I used to dream
about home every night.
- [Mike] And after that?
- Why I gave up
dreaming, it was hopeless
to try and penetrate the jungle.
(sighing)
I used to have the
natives take me out on
what you might call
hunting expeditions
but they led nowhere.
- [Tom] Then I just
had a hamburger
and some french fried potatoes.
- I know, and my only hold on
them depends on their belief
that I'm a goddess.
- And so Leona Helmsley's
empire was built.
- If we're to get out of
here alive, you must tell Bob
not to make any false moves.
- [Joel] Oh like killing people?
- [Greta] He's got to be
patient until tomorrow morning.
- Are you sure you
can trust Wanama?
- Wanama would do
anything for me.
- Wanama's phenomena.
- She's the only one I can trust
to lead us out of the jungle.
- Bob has a hand compass.
- [Joel] And some
french fried potatoes.
- In case anything goes wrong.
I think you'd better leave now.
- You always say something
like that just when
I'm beginning to enjoy myself.
- [Tom] Then I gotta wait a
few minutes before I can leave.
- Well that's life.
Hey what is this,
where did you get this?
- Wanama made it for me.
- Hmm world's greatest grandma.
- Hey, where did Wanama get
the stuff she carved this from?
- On the outskirts
of the village, why?
- [Joel] Why?
- [Tom] Wanama's working
through a lot of pain isn't she?
- I guess you don't,
I saw something
just like this in Colorado.
- Well what is it?
- Unless I'm crazy
it's cronotite.
Of course that wouldn't
mean anything to you either.
Cronotite is stuff they
use in the manufacture
of atomic energy.
- [Tom] Subcellular
power if you're a visitor
from a foreign planet.
- Are you serious?
- Of course I'm serious!
Look Bob knows a lot
about his kind of thing.
You mind if show it to him?
- Not if you want to.
- Hey I can take
target practice on it.
- If it is cronotite we'll
organize our own expedition
and come back for it.
- Provided we get out
of here alive Mike.
- [All] Womp, womp,
womp, womp, wah.
(upbeat music)
- [Tom] Hmm, tastes
like grandpa.
- It's cronotite alright.
- You sure?
- I'd stake my life on it.
- That's already
in the kitty Bob.
- You know what this means?
- I don't know what it
means to you, but personally
I've had my eye on
a ranch in Colorado
ever since I was a kid.
- [Joel] Oh yeah, like I care.
- Nagara's still on guard,
our best chance is to make
a break for it just before dawn.
- Wait a minute, Greta's
worked out a plan for us.
- [Tom] Hey, when did you
start calling her Greta?
- She'd just get in the way.
- [Tom] She told me
to call her goddess.
- We're not getting
through that jungle without
being slowed down by a dame.
- Well if we get through,
and I doubt very much we can
Ulanga'd be a
cinch to blame her.
Have you ever stopped to
think what those natives
might do to her?
- [Tom] Oh yeah.
- That's her lookout,
she's the white goddess,
she can figure a
way out of this.
- Suppose they kill her?
- We don't have to
bring her back alive
to collect the reward.
And besides that's
peanuts alongside
what well collect on this.
- Hey your horns
are showing Bob!
- I'm taking this back to Greta.
Bob I'm gonna be kind to you.
- [Joel] I'm gonna
put you to sleep.
- The spot you're on
has twisted your mind.
Nobody can be that
much of a heel!
- [Joel] But I can.
- [Tom] I can, really I can.
- Yeah sure you can.
- Don't go away I can really.
- Don't go heel like he is.
- [Tom] Why are
they looking at me?
Get that camera off of me!
- [Joel] I'm a heel.
- [Tom] We'll be back
right after this.
- [Joel] I'm still a heel.
- [Tom] Such a heel.
- I appreciate the fact that
I can't leave this hole,
but is there any reason why
I can't have some water?
- Water?
- If it isn't too much trouble.
- Wanama.
Bring white devil water.
(speaking foreign language)
- Yeah, bring a lot of it,
and don't forget the ice.
- Ice?
- Skip it.
- Skip it?
- Oh and Wanama bring it inside,
- Inside?
- it's hotter than
blazes out here.
- Blazes?
- I've arranged to send
all the natives out
on a hunting expedition
early tomorrow morning,
that will enable us
to travel by daylight.
- What about Nagara?
- You'll have to tie him up.
But I don't want him
hurt, understand?
- You mean you don't trust him?
- I don't dare, after
all he is a Zambezi.
These natives are very
peculiar and childlike.
- [Tom] They don't even shoot
things they don't understand.
- If he knew what we were up to.
- Now what makes you think
you can trust Wanama?
- Oh I know I can,
after all she's been
my constant companion
for six years.
- Tell me Wanama, you know the
jungle pretty well don't you?
- Oh I get around are
you really an astronaut?
- I guess you are at that.
Would you remember where
(speaking foreign
language) Greta came from?
- She's a temp right?
- The gods send (speaking
foreign language) Greta.
- Is that what she told you?
- Oh no, but we know.
Everybody know.
- You love (speaking foreign
language) very much don't you?
- Oh sure, everybody
love (speaking foreign
language) Greta.
- Then you'd want to help her
if she needed you wouldn't you?
- Help (speaking
foreign language) Greta?
- [Joel] Come on get to the
point, cut to the chase!
- Something bad happen
to (speaking foreign
language) Greta?
- It will if we don't help her.
- Okay what about the rifles?
- I had to have them destroyed.
The natives thought they
were weapons of evil.
(laughter)
- They're kinda kooky
and silly that way.
(laughter)
Yes, the jungle's infested
with wild animals.
- [Tom] So am I.
- Well if we should
get in a spot
you can always exert your
powers white goddess.
- [Tom] Oh that's
rich, kill him.
- Mike, do you
think you could get
Bob's revolver away from him?
I don't trust him.
- No, he'd never give it up.
- Then we'll just have
to take our chances.
- Now don't worry Greta.
- [Tom] I'm the man of
steel, can stop bullets,
the whole nine yards.
- [Greta] You know it'd
serve him right if we
turned him over to
the tender mercies
of Ulanga the witch doctor.
- Here, here, we
couldn't do that.
- Let me just
patronize you a bit.
- You know Mike, I think
you're absolutely right.
He's undoubtedly
become unbalanced by
all that's happened.
- [Tom] Yeah he's not
thinking as clearly as when
he shot that guy.
- Have to watch
him very closely.
- Relax goddess, relax.
(laughing)
- What's the matter Wanama?
- Yeah kitten why the long face?
- Me wanna talk (speaking
foreign language) Greta alone.
- That's alright, you may
speak, he's our friend.
- His friend white devil too.
Please (speaking
foreign language) Greta
Wanama wanna speak
with you alone.
- [Joel] What's
the matter Wananna?
- No, I have a feeling this
concerns the both of us.
What happened Wanama,
were you with white devil?
- [Tom] Or should I get out
the anatomically correct doll?
- Are you afraid to
tell me what happened?
- No.
Please me wanna talk
(speaking foreign
language) Greta alone.
- (speaking foreign language)
Greta want you to speak now.
- [Joel] Get on with it.
- Get on with it please!
- White devil want me
take him through jungle.
- Alone?
- He say that way
we help (speaking
foreign language) Greta
but Wanama not believe.
- You didn't tell him you
were coming here did you?
- Oh no, Wanama dumb.
♪ Wanama dumb doo doo do do do ♪
♪ Wanama dumb doo doo doo do ♪
- Be careful Mike.
- [Tom] So did you do it?
- (speaking foreign
language) Greta,
(speaking foreign
language) Greta love him?
- [Joel] Isn't there a
magazine devoted to this?
- [Mike] I'll take that Bob.
- What are you daffy?
- No I'm Porky you're
Daffy remember?
- I don't think so, we're
pulling out tomorrow morning.
And Greta and I both decided
that it will be better
if I pack the artillery
on this little safari.
- Yeah see?
- Oh you and Greta
decided did ya?
Well you go on back to Greta
and do some more deciding.
- [Tom] Yeah says you.
- It's my piece of iron
and I'm gonna keep it.
- Give me that.
- [Tom] 1942!
Man of steel huh?
Phone this into Perry White.
- Now I'm packing the rod.
- [Joel] Yeah that's right.
- [Tom] Get up off
of the table oh.
- [Joel] Visitor from
another planet, hey!
- Far beyond mortal man.
Oh you got a little
on your chin there.
- [Tom] All this Pier
One stuff collapses.
Hey look, native
collapsing furniture.
Looks so real.
- It sure does.
(speaking foreign language)
- Guano hit fan!
- [Tom] I will kill
you, I will kill him.
- Faster than a speeding.
- [Tom] Yeah right, more
powerful than a wimp.
- [Joel] Oh great, that's
twice in the same week.
- You fool!
- I didn't mean to shoot
him, it was an accident!
- Oh great, now he's got a line.
(speaking foreign language)
- [Tom] He's never
gonna like you now Bill.
- [Joel] Off to
deliver more flowers.
- Nothing can stop Ulanga
he's going after the hunters.
Well have to stop now
without Wanama before Ulanga
reaches the tribe.
- You're not gonna
go without me.
- We should leave
you here but come on.
- Go to my place and wait.
- [Tom] She's just
gonna pack a few things.
- Okay Greta come on.
- Come on junior let's
get off this picture.
Besides I wanna get home
and shoot holes in Gary.
- [Joel] Oh it's
just a through hole.
Greta give him a new heart sac.
- [Tom] Yeah, yeah bathe it
in cool water, put a pulpice
on it, I gotta beat cheeks.
- You take care of him
just as I taught you.
(speaking foreign
language) must leave now.
They will take me back
where I came from.
- (speaking foreign language)
Greta no come back to Wanama?
- I don't know, you
be a good girl Wanama,
and remember everything
I've taught you.
- [Tom] How to make
the scene darker.
- I'll remember everything
you've taught me.
- [Tom] I got to blow, see ya.
- (speaking foreign
language) Greta.
- Nobody taught anybody to act.
- Skipper!
- [Tom] Little bunny.
- Skipper.
- [Tom] Hey Bob, there's a
living thing why don't you
swing into high and kill it.
(chuckles)
- Skipper!
- [Tom] Little bunny.
- Skip-per.
Hey Bill when you were
a kid and you got pets
did you kill 'em?
And hey what did happen
to your sister anyway?
(speaking foreign language)
(banging on drum)
- [Tom] Oh no no no, I
didn't say start the band.
I hate 'em.
- Hey we eat tonight.
- [Joel] Hey you
never saw that tree
before you wanna kill it Bob?
- [Tom] We gotta get out of
here, we gotta get out of here.
- [Joel] Why don't we just
torch the whole continent
Bob would you like that?
- We'd better hurry.
(yelling)
- What in the sam
scratch is that noise?
- It sounds like a mosquito
about the size of your head
just got sucked in
through the access ports.
- Oh don't be absurd a mosquito
couldn't live in a vacuum.
Hey, there's a ship
coming into range!
- Hey Cambot give us
a rocket number nine
let's see what it looks like.
Hey that's no mosquito, the
British stopped using those
at the end of the war.
- [Tom] Hey look
something's coming in
on the hex field view screen.
- Stop that, stop it!
- We're not sure if we
don't understand them yet.
- Sorry, sorry.
- [Joel] Hey what
do you guys want?
- We want to shoot you.
- Stop that, stop it, you can't
shoot through a view screen.
- Oh sorry, I'm sorry.
- Let me.
Hello, greetings,
insignificant life forms.
We come bearing gifts.
Beads, trinkets, Coke
bottles, accessories.
- And bullets.
- [Croooow] Joel, what
the heck do they want?
- Actually our needs
are rather simple,
I brought a little list.
All we need is, ah here
it is mineral rights.
Women, property,
scalps, food, clothing,
it's the standard list.
Oh and also we want the
cute one's head if we could.
- [Tom] That must be you Joel.
- [Croooow] Yeah definitely
Joel, neither one of us, yeah.
- [Joel] Hey quiet you
guys we're talking to
an alleged higher life
form whatever that means.
- That's us.
(shooting gun)
- If you could just pop
that stuff over to our ship
we'd greatly appreciate it.
Oh, I brought a little
treat for you too.
The magic fire stick.
Also the ball in the cup trick.
- We also brought VD,
smallpox, and the widow maker.
(shooting gun)
- Stop that you idiot.
Now, Mr. Joel.
You are a white man with
strange looking slave types,
why haven't you
exploited them yet?
- Or at least shot them?
- Hey listen you two,
these two slave types
happen to be my friends and
I don't know where you two
get off waltzing
around geosynchronous
orbit trying to throw
your white male weight around,
you got another thing coming.
You're messing with
the satellite of love.
- I see, did you
enjoy the terrine?
The radicchio was picked fresh.
Kill them.
(shooting gun)
- Oh brother.
Man, we gotta stop giving our
address out you know that?
(upbeat music)
(soft music)
- Oh.
- Hold it!
What's the matter Greta?
- [Greta] I twisted my ankle.
- Oh come on.
- [Tom] Let me get his
straight, you survived
in the jungle for six years,
and now you're telling me
you just sprained your entire
ankle on a piece of moss?
Get real.
- [Joel] Well she threw a
shoe, that means I'm gonna
have to shoot her.
- That's Bob's department.
- That's all we need.
- [Joel] That's all we need.
- [Tom] All we need.
- Now we have to
look out for her.
- Got any ideas.
- [Tom] No it's just
my watch, it growls at
the top of the hour.
(chuckles)
Jerry would you
hand me that device.
- [Joel] Okay now this
is a nine, and I already
have it in a 10.
- Snuggy, snuggy.
- You better rest there for
a few minutes more Greta.
- A few minutes more?
- [All] A few minutes more?
- It'll be dark pretty
soon, and we're a long ways
from the plane.
- We're going just
as fast as we can,
and that's just as
fast as we're gonna go.
- He's right Mike
we've got to get going.
- [All] Shut up!
- I have to be alright.
- Well then come on,
let's go, come on.
- Okay Galahad get moving.
- [Joel] Don't you ever
call me Galahad again ever!
- [Tom] Meanwhile in an
equally racist Tarzan movie
across the way.
- Hey you ho daddy surf's up.
- [Joel] Oh cool Leopard
I wonder if it's Def?
(cheers)
- [Tom] Good one dude.
- Dec, dec man.
- [Greta] Can't we
stop just a minute?
- [Mike] Hold it.
- [Tom] I haven't seen a
Port-A-Potty in 10 miles.
- Here just sit on this
conveniently placed stone.
- You alright?
- May I have some water?
- Sure.
- White goddess having trouble?
- [Tom] White fascist
getting smart?
- Make one wise crack too many,
then you're not gonna feel
like making anymore wise cracks.
- Yeah and if we keep
stopping for her we won't
make any cracks
wise or otherwise.
- [Joel] Ooh good one.
- You better go on
without me Mike.
- Are you serious?
- Yes, there's still
a chance for you two.
And if Ulanga and the
natives catch up with me
maybe I'll still have
enough power to save myself.
- [Tom] Okay, bye.
- Why not do what she says Mike?
They won't harm her,
she's the white goddess,
she can bluff her way out
of it, it's our only chance.
- Forget it.
- But how are you?
- I said forget it!
- [Tom] Forgotten sir.
- They haven't caught us
so far, we'll just keep
our fingers crossed.
That a girl, it'll
be dark pretty soon.
If we're gonna get out of
here alive we'll have to
use our heads, so if
you've got any ideas,
now's the time to spill 'em.
- [Tom] Well I kinda do.
- Up to now my ideas
haven't carried much weight.
So I'll leave it to
you two masterminds.
- [Tom] Okay, I had
that one coming.
- Well there's only
one thing we can do.
We'll never make it through
the jungle at night.
We'll have to build a fire
to keep the animals away
and stay close to it until dawn.
- Are you crazy that's
all we need a fire
to show Ulanga where we are?
- Ulanga and the natives
will be doing the same thing
we're doing.
- [Joel] Yeah that's what
I was thinking you know?
- Safety.
- How do you know they will?
- I know their superstitions
and their fears.
- [Joel] Hey, I'm talking here!
- And there on handle was
spear, no really, this is it.
(growling)
- [Tom] Hey, where the
hell is the MGM one?
Jimminy I got a film to make.
- [Joel] You think you
got problems I'm opening
for Siegfried and Roy.
- [Tom] I hate Mondays.
- Hey, wait for me I got a
cameo in this film, wait up!
- [Joel] You think
Mellencamp is a dumb name?
- [Tom] Yeah.
- [Joel] Really?
- So there on the handle
was a hook, no really.
- You should probably
get some sleep Greta.
- I'm not tired.
- Are you kidding?
You're so tired you're
about ready to come apart.
- Well maybe I am, but
I could sit up all night
talking about home.
Tell me some more Mike.
(growling)
- [Tom] Ooh you are hungry.
- Everything since Pearl Harbor.
What else would
you like to know?
- [Joel] I just love
listening to their voices.
- What kind of hats
are the women wearing?
- Hats?
- [Tom] Hats.
- Now why would you ask
me a thing like that?
How would I know anything
about women's hats?
I never look at their hats.
- Their underwear yes.
- Anyway, are they cute?
- Greta they're hats.
- [Joel] Oh don't pretend
you haven't worn any Reeves.
(chuckles)
- You know something?
- What?
Hats.
- Hats.
- It'd look alright on you.
- Hey you guys, why
don't you get some sleep?
What are you talking about?
- Hats.
Hats.
- [All] Hats.
- [Joel] Hats!
- God it will be good to
get back to a good hot tub.
(laughing)
- [Tom] Maybe sooner
than you think.
- Try and get some sleep.
- What about you?
- I'm gonna keep an eye on
our boyfriend over there.
- He's your boyfriend,
you're the one
who invited the bossa angle.
(animal chittering)
- [Joel] Hey, quit
laughing back there.
- [Tom] Say Bill, don't look
now, I think your kneecaps
are on fire.
(soft music)
- You're my little rag doll.
- [Tom] Did you
leave a wake up call?
- Well I'm off!
- [Tom] The jungle,
extending me a welcome.
(chuckles)
- [Joel] He's really a good man,
and tomorrow is another day.
(soft music)
- [Tom] Well I think I'll
just burn this drive in
bank canister here.
Smells good.
- [Joel] So every time
I ate a burger an acre
of this stuff disappears,
I don't get it?
(soft music)
- I'm ready again.
- [Tom] Watch it hand.
Look out he's got a gun!
Oh sorry.
(soft music)
(growling)
Hey pipe down, this is
the smoking section.
(upbeat music)
- Bob, Mike, please this
isn't getting us anywhere.
Please!
- [Tom] Hey what the
heck is going on here?
Go away they're
sleeping, wake up
they're beating the
cheese out of each other.
- Must be the heat.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Now I'll just
take the savages things
and get out of here.
- Well Mike, he really
kicked your butt.
- Mike, Mike!
- That coulda been
a paper drill.
- [Joel] Oh no.
- [Tom] Shouldn't have
stopped for breakfast.
- [Joel] No uh oh.
- [Tom] You had to order
french fried potatoes.
My fault.
- Where's?
- He's gone.
(whimpering)
- The gun and the compass?
- They're gone too.
- We'll never find the
plane without that compass!
- [Tom] I'll rub you on a
rock and you'll magnetize.
- [Mike] Let's go!
- He went through those bushes.
- Oh could you be a
little more vague?
- Come on let's go!
- [Joel] Is it
alright for me to say
he took his pith helmet?
- Yes but not now.
- [Tom] Crickets.
I hear crickets,
big crickets, whoa.
(growling)
Whoa!
Take that!
- Don't forget to limp.
- How's the ankle?
- Oh alright.
- Good girl.
- [Croooow] Keep hobbling
or I'll have to chew it off.
- [Joel] You know I'd
really like to get ahold
of that Gary Larson
guy once and for all.
- [Tom] Ever get pieces of
flesh caught in your teeth?
- I hate that.
Mm, fresh tracks and
one of them is limping.
(speaking foreign language)
- [Tom] A lot of scat.
- [Joel] Hey wait for us
they wouldn't take our visa.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Doe!
Oh I forgot to wind my compass,
now I'm really gonna be late.
(dramatic music)
- [Croooow] Geez I
hope none of my friends
see me with her.
- [Joel] Hi it's me again,
hope you're enjoying
the show brought to you by
our friends at Hunt Wesson.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] If this is a
first date you don't mind
if I don't call
you again do you?
(dramatic music)
- Oh my ankle, it's all
hot and it hurts and stuff.
- No I've got to keep going,
if he gets too far ahead
we'll never find him.
- [Joel] I have a
confession to make,
we lost the trail
four miles back.
- Look Greta!
- [Tom] Awe heck, that
could be anybody's.
- At least we're on the
right track, come on.
(dramatic music)
- Oh that's great Mike,
what else can we do with it?
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Oh, are we still
in this film or what?
(dramatic music)
Hey that's him, oh no,
hey where's Ted Vessel?
(soft music)
- [Joel] Let's watch the fun.
(laughing)
(soft music)
- [Tom] Oh great he
killed a coconut.
- [Joel] In cold milk.
- Come on honey.
- What did you call me Mike?
- I called you.
(groaning)
- [Joel] Brother.
- Bow wow.
- [Joel] Bungle in the jungle.
Hear a coconut fall,
what's going on?
(monkey shrieking)
- [Joel] Oh stop screaming
I didn't even hit you!
- [Tom] Someone outta
spank that monkey.
(dramatic music)
- Here whitey, whitey,
whitey, whitey.
- [Tom] Here Caucasian,
here Caucasian.
- Here whitey, whitey,
whitey, whitey.
- [Tom] Caucasian.
- Me got idea sprinkle trail
with Cheez Whiz, white bread,
Velveeta, white
devil can't resist.
- [Tom] Whitey.
(soft music)
(growling)
- [Joel] Hey remember
that time you took
a pot shot at me pretty boy?
Well it's time to
ante up, ya dig?
- [Tom] Take that
you stinking coconut.
(dramatic music)
- Can't go through there.
Oh, no, ugh.
Oh, gah, oh I'm sick
of you old vines.
I meant to do that.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Huh, an entire jungle
and I slip on a banana peel.
That's irony for you.
I'm still right over
your shoulder smart guy.
Coconut take that.
Hmm, sounded like a car
backfiring didn't it?
- Yeah that ankle healed quick.
(chuckles)
- [Tom] Continuity, script girl.
- I invade Poland, oh,
(speaking foreign
language) where are you?
Mine buddies.
(screaming)
- [Tom] Oh quit screaming,
I'm sorry about the coconut.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Try to replace
your divets please.
- [Tom] Really.
- No.
We are on our way.
- [Joel] Hey, hey you
two, he's over there.
- [Tom] Somebody didn't
replace their divets.
- [Joel] They're in this movie.
- Look we made it
there's the plane.
- [Joel] And it's just landing.
(soft music)
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Let's get off sets.
- [Croooow] Goddess droppings.
- [Tom] Working overtime.
(dramatic music)
Those two just don't get
along with each other do they?
(dramatic music)
Ooh bingo.
My first kill feels good.
- Oh white people evil,
let's get out of here Scooby.
- He's dead, the poor
devil he must've gone
completely out of his mind.
- [Tom] He's dead,
she's mine, I'm in love,
we're out of here goodnight!
(crowd screaming)
- Hey it looks like
your in laws are coming.
- [Tom] Uh oh.
- Ulanga, Ulanga!
(speaking foreign language)
- [All] Hail Dorothy, the
wicked witch doctor is dead.
Hail Dorothy!
- Looks even realer taking off.
- [Tom] Okay, new
rule, no white people.
Must take hard line on
this, no exceptions.
Send memo.
- [Joel] I told you this
thing had an automatic pilot.
(upbeat music)
(snoring)
- Wait 'til you get a look
at that country Greta.
Colorado's the most beautiful
state in the whole universe.
And that ranch I picked out.
Alfalfa, wheat.
- [Tom] Stimey, Spanky.
- Hey you aren't listening
to a word I'm saying.
- Uh huh.
- Sounds great.
- What are you thinking about?
- I'm just wondering how
I'm gonna look in
one of those hats.
- [Tom] Huh?
Hats.
- [Joel] Hat?
(laughing)
- That's great, hats.
(upbeat music)
♪ There was a fungal
in the jungle ♪
♪ That caused a
real big fright ♪
♪ Someone was made a goddess
and she happened to be white ♪
♪ But then she was rescued
and now she's in the states ♪
♪ She's just your
average housewife ♪
♪ A cleaning up the place ♪
♪ My my my ♪
♪ My white goddess ♪
(soft music)
(applause)
- Well you can just tell
them if they're not going to
worship me I'm not
going to join their PTA!
(laughter)
- Hi honey I'm home.
(applause)
- Oh how was work today?
- Boy, it's a jungle out there!
(laughter)
- Well, aren't you gonna
bow down and kiss my feet?
- Hey, you may be
queen of the jungle
but I wear the
khakis around here.
(cheers and applause)
Hey what's this mess?
- Oh, it's our neighbor,
that friend of yours.
- Bill?
Did he go on another
wild shooting spree?
- I'll say he did and
this time he went too far.
he went and shot
up my crock pot.
I'm not going to be
able to make dinner!
- Well, I told ya he
wasn't such a bad guy.
(laughter)
(shooting gun)
- I wish that man would learn
how to use the doorbell!
(laughter)
- [Tom] Hello everybody.
(applause)
- Will you cut that out?
- Oh now stop it you two, stop
it, would you settle down?
Mr. and Mrs. Mabudhawan
are on their way
over here to play bridge.
- [Tom] What where?
(gun shooting)
- [Man] Oh God.
(groans)
- [Tom] Maybe it'll be
three-card Monte now.
(laughter)
- I'm so sorry Mrs. Mabuto
that we shot your husband.
What were his last words?
(speaking foreign language)
- What did she say?
- [Tom] Sounded like (speaking
made up foreign language)
(laughter)
- Well that's one native
that's not going to
be restless tonight.
(laughter)
- Baby, you're a goddess.
(sighs)
(applause)
- Mm how sweet it is, Tom Servo.
Art Croooow, Sheila McGypsy!
The Miami Beach audiences
the greatest audiences
in the world
goodnight everybody!
(cheers and applause)
(laughing)
- Frank!
- Oh that was funny
man that was even
funnier than an occasional
wife, even CPO Sharkey.
- Listen you hockey pork
they've got letters to read!
- Sure I got 'em right here.
I really appreciate
you scientist faxing
these up for us.
But this one is from Margaret
Banister okay and show that on
the still store Cambot.
- [Croooow] Oh she's sweet.
- See that cute
picture and everything?
Dear Joel I like your
movies, you're really funny.
I'm five years old,
really everything you
want to know about
people when they write.
- I think so.
- Croooow is really funny.
- Thank you.
- And Tom is too.
- And I don't know she must
have forgot about you Gypsy.
- She thinks you're funny too!
- I'm sure she would think
you're funny too and she
sent us actually two
pictures along with a photo
put that one on Cambot.
- [Tom] Cool!
- [Croooow] That's really nice.
- And then we got this one
too, which I really like.
I thought it was kind of cool
how she just drew it black
where she didn't know what
the bottom of our
bodies looked like.
- That's imagination for ya.
- But you see.
- Oh there it is.
- Yeah that's what
it looks like.
- [Croooow] Missing the
rest of my dressing now.
- Well I guess that
ends the experiment sirs
I hope you enjoyed
this skits and stuff.
- Joel can I say
the address please?
- Oh yeah, better do that.
- Send your letters,
drawings and whatever
to the Mystery Science
Theater Information Club
post office box 5325
Hopkins, Minnesota
the zip code is 55343.
Keep 'em coming.
- Right and I guess that
ends the experiment sir.
- Well very nice clambake.
- Until next time Jolie Rainy.
- Okay Frank push the button.
- What?
- Would you push the button?
- Just push the button.
- Oh God.
(dramatic music)